CALEB CARNETT

North Bethesda, Maryland | 830-312-8326 <u>carnett.caleb@gmail.com</u> <u>Github</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Full-Stack Software Developer with 1+ years of experience in Javascript, React, node.js, and MongoDB to build user-friendly web applications. With a passion for continuous learning, overcoming challenges, and constantly striving to push my boundaries. 3+ years of experience in project management and customer service have enabled me to develop strong problem-solving and collaboration skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, GraphQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Git, GitHub, Heroku, jQuery, MySQL, NoSQL, REST APIs, Object Oriented Programming(OOP), Mobile Responsive Design, Express.js, MVC

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Cool-Beans | Github Live Site

- Full-stack MERN E-commerce application for coffee enthusiasts.
- Collaborated on building a feature-rich platform enabling users to add products to a cart, leave reviews, and seamlessly complete transactions using a built-in Stripe API.

PawFriends | Github

- Full-stack application facilitating pet adoption
- Codeveloped and deployed an MVC-based application allowing users to post and adopt rescued pets, leveraging technologies like JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL, Express.js, Heroku, and Handlebars.js.

Movie Night | Github

 Co-created a web app that fetches data from multiple RESTful APIs, providing users with movie details, trailers, and facts in one convenient location.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Meritage Homes

Hybrid/San Antonio, TX

February 2022 - November 2022

Warranty Manager

- Managed and closed over 1500 warranty claims issues through Salesforce within 9 months
- Reduced total warranty claim backlog by over 50% within 6 months by collaborating with team members
- Increased customer satisfaction scores by 8% by solving technical home-owner issues within 2 weeks

Pratt Industries

San Antonio, TX

Account Manager

July 2021 - February 2022

- Led and maintained relationships with 2 accounts generating over \$200,000 in monthly sales
- Increased warehouse space by 30% minimizing lost profits on aged inventory
- Grew company revenue by \$15,000 each month by identifying customer needs and promoting new products

Avco Roofing

San Antonio, TX

Project Manager

January 2020 - July 2021

- Collaborated on a sales campaign for \$1,400,000 in revenue by designing refined sales strategies and techniques
- Managed and coordinated construction crews of up to 20 employees on residential properties
- Facilitated and initiated the project vision, planning, design, and implementation of projects

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at San Antonio

Remote

Certificate of completion - Full Stack Web Developer (MERN)

April 2023

The University of Texas at San Antonio

Bachelor of Business Administration, concentration in Marketing

San Antonio, TX December 2019